# RAMSAY GONZALEZ

13304 Francisco Way | Mt Laurel, NJ 08054 (856) 203-2107 | ramsay.gonzalez@icloud.com

#### **PROFILE**

Dedicated and experienced professional with a history of superior performance. Over a decade of experience in the fields of operations and program management. Excellent team member able to develop positive relationships in the workplace. Proven team leader capable of maximizing productivity and meeting deadlines. Ability to learn quickly and work independently. **Active DoD Secret security clearance.** 

### **SKILLS & ABILITIES**

- Ability to multitask and prioritize; mastered during years of working in fast paced environments.
- Effective collaborator; ability to work with cross-functional teams to solve problems and achieve goals.
- Excellent communicator at all organizational levels; strong written and verbal communication skills (reports & presentations).
- Innovative problem solver; ability to develop and implement process improvement.
- Skilled SAP & Solumina user; experience in large volume manufacturing.
- Accomplished Microsoft Access application and SQL Server database developer.
- Proficient with Microsoft Tools; Word,
   Power Point, Excel, Project, SharePoint.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Training & Development Manager, Leidos / Lockheed Martin

July 2016 – Present

Marlton, NJ / Kabul, Afghanistan

- Responsible for the proper training, progression, and tracking of over 500 Afghan military students in their assigned Military Occupation Specialty (MOS) across three locations in Afghanistan.
- Liaison between program leadership and USG; ensure all program training requirements are met and customer requests remain within the scope of our performance work statement.
- Ensure instructors conduct training in accordance with the performance work statement, operating
  instructions, and all other applicable regulations.
- Host weekly internal meeting with functional managers and Bi-Weekly/Monthly meetings with USG to review program performance and address issues as needed.
- Data manager for all training and flight operations data. Maintain three databases, generate reports, troubleshoot errors, and provide continuous capability improvements.

## Special Accomplishments

- Developed, launched, and provided training for three Microsoft Access applications with Microsoft SQL Server database back-ends (currently used program wide OCONUS):
  - Flight Operations Tool: Modernized and streamlined the ability of Flight Operations Controllers to document and report flight operations data.
  - o Employee Training Record (ETR): Used to track all OCONUS CLS Personnel medical, certifications, and training (GOP, CENTCOM, Read & Sign) status. Replaced the employee training record six part folders. Generates reports to keep managers and employees informed of their requirement statuses.

- Afghan Training Database: Used to capture program mentoring and training efforts and generate student summaries, CDRL reports and other reports critical to keeping management and USG informed of training progress.
- Developed, launched, and provided training for new program SharePoint site. Efforts led to the
  consolidation of program data storage and simplified data sharing. Created several tools within the site to
  streamline processes.
- Assumed responsibility for the OCONUS employee-training program and successfully led the program to raising compliance levels from the low 60% mark to above 99% across each requirement area. Achieved this through the development and implementation of the ETR application mentioned above and spearheading a total revamp of training processes.

### Manufacturing Planner Sr, Lockheed Martin

May 2015 – July 2016

Moorestown, NJ

- Managed the flow of material from internal and external sources to fulfill assembly line requirements.
- Ensured availability of material and released orders to operators in a timely matter to meet work center production schedule.
- Maintained databases (SAP & Solumina), generated status reports, and briefed management on work center performance and material status.
- Work center "Operations Excellence" representative involved in continuous process and safety improvements.

# **Base Operations Controller Sr, Lockheed Martin**

May 2013 – May 2015

Greenville, SC

- Point of contact and approving authority for all aircraft ground and flights operations (refuel, defuel, engine runs, filing flight plans, preflight and post flight activities).
- Coordinated and ensured the proper response of support and maintenance personnel to cross-functional employee or customer requests.
- Initiated and managed the response of crisis services personnel to emergencies, including: employee injuries, fuel spills, ground emergencies, and inflight emergencies.

# Special Accomplishments

- Developed, launched, and provided training for three Microsoft Access applications with Microsoft SQL Server database back-ends (currently used facility-wide):
  - o Flight Operations Tool: (Awarded SRA Excellence Award July 2014) Modernized and streamlined the ability of Base Operations to document ground and flight operations data.
  - o Base Operations Log: Eliminates the need for hundreds of word documents each year. Enables controllers to search through thousands of entries using keywords.
  - Attendance Tool: Utilized by facility Operations Managers and Supervisors to input daily employee attendance related data.

# **Ground Management Program Operator, RVA Inc**

Apr 2012 – May 2013

John F. Kennedy Airport, NY

- Managed the flow of air traffic through Metering Control of departure flights on taxiways.
- Coordinated allocation of push times with ramp controllers utilizing the Sensis Aerobahn system.
- Determined the usability of and resolved problems with Aerobahn system and equipment.
- Hosted daily operations telephone conference with JFK airline carriers and other airport agencies.

### Air Traffic Controller (AFSC: 1C151), United States Air Force

October 2008 – November 2011

Joint Base McGuire Dix Lakehurst, NJ

- Formulated and issued ATC clearances and instructions to ensure the safe and expeditious flow of terminal ground and air operations to diverse airframes with various flight characteristics.
- Controlled VFR tactical arrivals and departures including conflicting and opposite direction operations.
- Coordinated aircraft movements and emergency information with radar controllers and other base agencies during normal day-to-day operations and during declared aircraft emergencies.

# Wing Operations Controller (AFSC: 1C351), United States Air Force August 2002 – October 2008 Various Duty Location CONUS & OCONUS

- Executive agent for Base Commander, coordinated activities such as establishing the Crisis Action Team, and the launch and recovery of the wing's 53 C-17 aircraft (valued over 10.6 billion dollars).
- Managed computer database Platforms; provided operational management of AMC aircraft and aircrew.
- Completed quick reaction checklist for ground/in-flight emergencies; to ensure response of emergency personnel.
- Managed day-to-day base operations; dispatched emergency response personnel, flight followed inbound and outbound aircraft, coordinated ramp/aircraft support activities, and performed other required administrative duties.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Embry Riddle Aeronautical University – Daytona Beach, FL – B.S Aeronautics

- Major: Aeronautics (94 Credits awarded toward degree, 26 remaining)
- Concentration: Airport Operations and Business Management
- Anticipated Graduation: Fall 2021

### University of Pennsylvania – Philadelphia, PA – Penn LPS Coding Bootcamp Certificate

- Concentration: An intensive 24-week-long bootcamp dedicated to designing and building web applications.
   Skilled learned include: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.JS, MySQL,
   MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, React.
- Anticipated Graduation: August 8<sup>th</sup>, 2020

# **AWARDS & RECOGNITION**

Special Recognition Cash Award (SRCA) for Exc	tellence Leidos, 2020
Merit Based In-Level Promotion	Leidos, 2017
Special Recognition Award (SRA) for Excellence	Leidos, 2017
Merit Based In-Level Promotion	Lockheed Martin, 2016
Merit Based In-Level Promotion	Lockheed Martin, 2014
Special Recognition Award (SRA) for Excellence	Lockheed Martin, 2014
Spot Team Award for Excellence	Lockheed Martin, 2013
Air Force Achievement Medal	United States Air Force, 2006
Commandant Leadership Award	United States Air Force - Airman Leadership School, 2006